Guide to the Duke Real Estate Office records, 1893-2018 and undated UA.10.04.0007
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Real Estate Easements, 1912-2006; undated
  - File No.: 3143, Grantee: Duke Universty, Grantor: City of Durham, Type: Agreement-Stormwater, 2005 July 15 (Box 33)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 4914, Page: 66, Comments/Location: Duke -South of Erwin Road
  - File No.: 3144, Grantee: Duke University, Grantor: Duke Power Co, Type: Easement, 1962 May 14 (Box 33)
    County: Orange, Comments/Location: N Hope Church Rd; Eno-Jamestown Transmission Line+K1833
  - File No.: 3145, Grantee: Tarheel Land & Timber, Grantor: Duke University, Type: Timber Deed, 2006 January 4 (Box 33)
    County: Durham, Deed Book: 5131, Page: 86, Comments/Location: McCracken land timber deed
  - Pinecrest Road Funds cards, 1924 December 30 - 1950 August 8 (Box 34)
    Includes information 18 cards containing lot numbers; file numbers; acreage; and remarks related to Pinecrest Road Funds.
  - Duke Homesites cards, 1966 June 3; 1973 March (Box 34)
    Includes information 3 cards containing lot numbers; file numbers; acreage; and remarks related to Duke Homesites.
  - Buncombe County, Highland Hospital, 1939-1973; 5 folders (Box 34)
    Includes File No. 555; 961; 1036; 1085; 1101; and 1116.
  - Southland Corporation, 1984 May 25; 27 folders (Box 34)
    Includes twenty-seven deeds donated by Southland Corporation to Duke university as part of a life estate.
- Administrative Files, 1925-2006
  For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use of administrative records. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist. Contact Research Services for more information.
  Includes reports and correspondence related to Maplewood Cemetery and the Urban Land Institute reports.
  - Maplewood Cemetery, 1993-2006; 2 folders (Box 35)
    Administrative restriction until 2020-2031.
    Includes correspondence regarding family plots; financials; and lot sales and transfers related to Maplewood Cemetery.
  - Urban Land Institute Panel Study, 1993; 2 folders (Box 35)
    Includes memoranda; correspondence; and committee meeting materials. Also includes the Duke University Urban Land Institute Study.
  - Land Resources Committee, 1988; 1989; 1991 (Box 35)
    Includes the Land Resources Committee report and recommendations.
  - Urban Land Institute Study #2, 1986-1987 (Box 35)
    Includes memoranda; correspondence; and the presentation of the Urban Land Institute panel to chief executive officers at Duke University.
  - Urban Land Institute Study #3, 1986-1991 (Box 35)
    Administrative restriction until 2020-2021.
    Includes memoranda and Duke University pamphlet related the the Urban Land Institute Study #2.
  - Maps and Reports, 1925-1996; 11 folders (Box 36)
    Access restricted. Collection contains potentially sensitive information and is restricted for 70 years from the date of creation (until 2056). Contact Research Services for Access.
    Includes survey maps for Section #1 and Section #2; Forest cover maps for: New Hope Creek Division, Duke Forest; Blackwood-Eno-Hillsboro Divisions, Duke Forest; and Durham Division, Duke Forest; deed and map indexes; Durham County tax maps no. 7, 8, 42, 50, 51, 97, 98, 102, 103, 175, 177, 178, 232, 236, and 798; and Duke Homesites Program and reports (including names, addresses and social security numbers of employees living in Duke Homesites.)